小步跑  来集合点见我们
How double time it, and meet us at the rally point?
到了后用对讲机通知我们
Radio back as soon as you're on post.
我们继续往东走
Let's just keep pushing east.
他们来杀我们了
They are coming for us.
看见两个人
Got a visual on two.
就在这一刻过来了
Coming for us at this very moment.
一群嗜血流氓和顽固不化的凶手
A powerful force of bloodthirsty rogues
组成的强大力量
and unrepentant cutthroats
决心要无情地消灭我们
bent on nothing short than our pitiless destruction.
距离大概50码
...about 50 yards, on their way.
但我依然在笑
And yet I smile.
但卡萝尔依然在笑
And yet Carol smiles.
为什么  老大
Why, boss?
他们也许人多势众
They probably have the numbers.
但我们足智多谋
But we have strategy.
是的
Yes, we do.
我心怀希望
I am binding a hope to my heart,
或许这不明智
perhaps unwisely...
但我们已经走了这么远
but we have come this far,
我们所有人依然在
all of us, still here.
如果我们遵守计划  遵循训练
If we follow this plan, if we keep to our training,
如果命运继续眷顾我们
if the fates continue to shine brightly upon us,
让我们
allowing us this...
梦想不灭
this dream?
我们一个士兵也不会失去
We will lose not one of our ranks.
一个也不会
Not one.
我们继续前行
We move onward.
《行尸走肉》
放下枪  立刻
Guns down. Now.
你真是亚历山大的瑞克啊
So, you're the Rick from Alexandria.
一直以来都是你
This whole time, it was you.
你叫人来这里毫无用处
You called your men in for nothing.
战斗在外面
The fight's out there.
这里只有我
It's just me in here.
你听到我刚才说的话了吗
Did you hear what I just said?
我知道你是谁
I know who you are.
门开着  我通过镜子看到了
I saw it in the mirror through the open door.
那可不是旧日故人
And it wasn't any kind of blast from the past.
我一看到你
As soon as I saw you...
就知道你跟我走过了同样的一段路
I knew you'd made the same trip as me.
从那里到这里
From there to here.
该死
Shit, well...
我猜我们都变了  对吧
Well, I guess we aren't the same guys we used to be, huh?
因为你就是个禽兽
'Cause you're a monster.
我叫他们来  是因为抓你有奖  瑞克
I called them back because you're a prize, Rick.
上面吩咐过了
We've been told.
我们不能杀你  寡妇和国王
We don't kill you, the Widow, or the King...
除非不得不杀
not if we don't have to.
你为什么来这里  瑞克
So why are you here, Rick?
我了解你
I know you...
就跟之前一样
Just like before.
你一直是那个愿意冲在最前面的人
You're always the guy willing to rush in.
但是为什么
But why?
你在找什么
What is it you're looking for?
无话可说吗
Nothing to say, huh?
没关系
It doesn't matter.
已经不要紧了
Not anymore.
对你而言
Not for you
对其他你带来的人而言都一样
or anyone else you brought in here.
因为我们这边剩下的人...
'Cause what's left of my people...
他们要过来了
They're coming.
我们会把你送到尼根那里
And we'll get you to Negan.
或者不会
Or we won't.
不管怎样
Either way,
我们都会把你解决了  香饽饽
we're gonna settle your shit, Peaches.
加油  大家一起挺住了
Come on, let's stay together!
后撤
Falling back!
我冲了
I'm going in!
停火  停火
Hold fire! Hold fire!
莫拉莱斯让我们进去
Morales wants us back inside!
所有人员听我命令到院门那边去
All force towards the courtyard door on my mark!
他们停火了
They stopped shooting.
主翼需要火力支援
On main flank, we need fire!
不  他们只是不朝我们开火了
No, they stopped shooting at us.
后援在哪里
Where's that backup?
背面遭到攻击
Fire from the rear!
上  上  进去
Go, go! Get in there!
上
Go!
这里  这里
Here. Here.
没事了  有我在
It's okay. I got you.
好了  好了
Okay, okay.
我在
I'm here.
情况有多糟
How bad is it?
有子弹穿过的伤口
There's an exit wound.
是好事
That's good.
我们可以把你送到神之国的医生那里去
We can get you to the Kingdom's doctor.
一直压着伤口就好
We just have to keep pressure.
埃里克
Eric.
我很抱歉...
I'm so sorry...
是你开枪打的我吗
Were you the one who shot me?
我...
I...
是我把你卷了进来  你根本不想战斗的
I pulled you into this. You didn't want to fight.
后来想了
Until -- Until I did.
你必须得帮助他们...
You need to help them --
-什么  我不能...  -你必须得走
- What? I can't -- - You need to go.
-我一个人在这也可以好好流血  -我不会抛下你的
- I can bleed here fine on my own -- - I'm not leaving you.
别犯傻
Don't be an idiot.
他们需要你
They need you.
亚伦  看着我
Aaron, look at me.
看着我
Look at me.
你知道我爱你
You know I love you.
你知道我是对的
You know I'm right.
好了
Okay.
现在
Now...
给我站起来
stand your ass up,
回到战场上去
get back to the fight,
打赢这场仗
and you win this thing.
我会的
I will. Okay.
我们会的
We will.
我爱你
I love you.
我早就预感到了
I always had a hunch.
走吧
Now go.
等我们回去  立刻报告玛姬
When we get back, we'll talk to Maggie.
她知道该如何处置这些人
She'll know what to do with them.
是啊
Yeah.
她知道
She will.
因为她清楚这些人做过什么
Because she knows what they did.
我们不远了
We're not far.
离山顶寨不远
From the Hilltop.
但应该离其他地方很远
We're far from somewhere else, I guess.
-我们已经做了决定  -还没板上钉钉
- We made our decision. - Nothing's been decided.
计划永远赶不上变化
Well, nothing's permanent except impermanence, I guess.
这点我赞同
In that way, I'll agree.
但我们要带他们去山顶寨
But we are taking these men to the Hilltop.
那是我们的去处
That's where we're going,
也是我们的计划
and that's what we're doing.
你知道这有多危险吗
You know how dangerous this is?
这些人有多坏
Who these people are?
无论他们做过什么
No matter what they've done...
他们毕竟是人
They're people.
危险有千万种
There's many kinds of danger,
死法也各不相同
many kinds of dying.
我杀人
I kill.
杀过人
I've killed.
你也杀人
You do.
杀过人
You have.
但我们不处死他人
But we don't execute.
我处死过
I have.
你家人在这里吗
Is your family here?
我们没能抵达伯明翰
We never made it to Birmingham.
他们没能
They didn't.
我很遗憾
Well, I'm sorry.
你当真吗  瑞克
Really, Rick?
是的
I am.
我也失去了一些人
I lost people, too.
洛莉
Lori.
肖恩
Shane.
安德莉亚
Andrea.
格伦
Glenn...
尼根杀了他
Negan killed him.
逼他下跪
Forced him to his knees.
然后当着我的面  当着他怀孕妻子的面
Bashed his head in right in front of me.
用棒子砸烂了他的头
In front of his pregnant wife.
他有妻子吗
He had a wife?
之前没有
Not before.
后来才遇见的
He met her.
在乱世中
In this?
对  在乱世中
Yeah. In this.
她就是那个寡妇
She's the Widow.
你也是尼根吗
Are you Negan, too?
我失去家人
I lost my family.
我丧失理智
I lost my mind.
我住在拖车里
I was in some... tow trailer,
醉生梦死
sleeping myself to death.
对未来毫无期待
Waiting to become nothing.
但救世军
And the Saviors --
他们找到了我
they found me.
他们认为我还有用
They thought I was worth a damn.
值得带我回去加入他们
Worth bringing back with 'em.
所以  没错
So, yeah.
我是尼根
Yeah, I'm Negan.
我能生存至今
To make it this far, this long,
唯有这个办法
I had to be.
我必须有所归属
I had to be something.
-和你一样  -我们不一样
- Just like you. - We're not the same. ?
怎么不一样
How's that?
-你看看你  -看我
- Well, look at you. - Look at me?
看看我们  瑞克
Look at us, Rick.
看看我们
Look at us.
我们就是两个为了生存不择手段的混蛋
We're two assholes ?who'll do whatever we have to just to keep going.
唯一的区别在于
And the only difference is
我手里握着枪
I'm the one holding the gun.
这不代表我比你坏  瑞克
That doesn't make me any worse than you, Rick --
我只是幸运一点
that just makes me luckier.
面对现实吧
'Cause let's face it,
如果不是我
if it wasn't me,
换作是你拿着枪
if it was you holding the gun,
我早就脑浆横流了
I'd be brains out on the floor right now.
-这你不知道  -而你又知道吗
- You don't know that. - And you do?
我知道我不愿意那么做
I know I wouldn't want to.
得了
Come on.
你能再假一点吗
Is that the best you can do?
我至少会试着寻找其他办法
I'd -- I'd at least try to find another way.
何必呢
Yeah? Why?
就因为我们早先认识过一两天吗
'Cause we knew each other for a few days back at the start?
我知道
Look, I know --
我不会...
I-I wouldn't -- I wouldn't just --
你知道我怎么想吗
You want to know what I think?
我想你可以随便怎么说
I think you can talk all you want.
随便花言巧语
You can say all the words.
洛莉  肖恩  安德莉亚  格伦
Lori, Shane, Andrea, Glenn...
他们全死了
They're all dead,
而早在某天某时
and somewhere along the way,
好好警官也随他们一起死了
Officer Friendly died right along with 'em.
就像我随家人死了一样
Just like I did with them.
我就这样想  瑞克
That's what I know, Rick.
等等  不
Wait, no!
你没事吧
You good?
-那是...  -我知道他是谁
- That -- t-that was... - I know who it was.
无所谓  一点关系都没有
It don't matter. Not one little bit.
找到枪了吗
You find them guns?
不在这里
They aren't here.
什么
What?
他把救世军从院子叫了回来
He called the Saviors back from the courtyard.
我们要离开这里  趁...
We gotta get out before --
他们来了
They're here.
知道吗  我一直想弄清楚
You know, I've been trying to figure out
你到底有什么不同
what's different about you.
因为肯定有什么不同
'Cause something's definitely different.
我终于弄明白了
I think I finally got it.
你的盔甲
It's your armor.
不一样
It's different.
更小
Smaller.
好像...
Almost like it --
缩水了之类的
like it shrunk or something.
该死
Oh, shit.
是那个孩子的吧
Was that the kid's? It is, isn't it?
为什么
Why the --
你为什么要穿这个
Why the hell would you wear that?
又没能保护到他
Didn't do shit for him.
山上有行尸
Walker's on the hill!
快走  快走  快走
Let's go! Let's go! Let's go!
快走  快走
Go! Go!
跟着他们  快点
Follow 'em! C'mon!
他们有枪  别跑
They got guns, huh? Stop!
天啊
God!
-我可不想死在这里  -快点
- Didn't make it this far to die! - Come on!
快点
C'mon! C'mon!
-快走  -往左
- Go! - Go left! Go left!
-不  -等等
- No! - Wait!
-起来  起来  -拉他起来  快
- Get up! Get up! Get up! - Get him up! Come on. Come on.
把他拉起来
Pull him up! Get him up! Get him up!
-等等  -起来
- Wait! - Get up.
别开枪  求求你  我们投降
Don't shoot! Please! We give up!
摩根  住手
Morgan. Stop.
快点  站起来  快走
C'mon. On your feet. Let's go.
他们逃跑了
They ran off to get away.
然后呢
Then what happens after?
-我们拦下了他们  -他们会继续逃
- We stopped them. - And they keep trying.
一次又一次
Again and again.
怎么  你以为他们会回来吗
What? You think they were gonna come back?
他们会变吗
That they will change?
他们会变成不一样的人吗
That they will be something else?
不会变的
It doesn't change.
永远不会变
It never changes.
-一旦变了...  -摩根
- Once you turn -- ?- Morgan.
我们会找到别的方法
We're gonna find another way.
玛姬会找到别的办法
Maggie will find another way.
你真觉得她不会杀死他们吗
Really think she won't want 'em dead?
一个不剩  在他们干了那么多坏事之后
Every last one? ?After what they've done?
不只是他们
And it isn't just them.
因为我们也站在这
'Cause we're here now,
这幅样子
to be this,
和他们做一样的坏事
do the same thing they do,
但我们继续
but we go on.
我们是一样的
You see, we are the same --
-摩根  -我们是一样的
- Morgan.- We're the same.
我们是一样的
We're the same,
所以别无选择
so there's no choice.
所有人都会变  但我们
Everybody turns, but w-we w--
有战争  之后就有和平
There's war, and then there's peace.
战争结束后我们要和这些人一起生活
We're gonna have to live with these people after.
我们必须找到和平共处的方法
We're gonna have to find a way to peace.
摩根
Morgan...
听清楚了
Make no mistake,
被我们迅速消灭的那些人
those we've so swiftly extinguished
很可能只是三大基地的其中一支驻军
are but perhaps one garrison in a compound of three.
但我们的首胜会带来第二次胜利
But our first victory will allow our second.
第二次会带来第三次
Our second will deliver our third.
快  我们走
Come on! Come on! Let's go!
安全
Clear.
该死
Damn it!
是他们
It's them!
那边  走
There! Go!
好了
Okay.
你现在有点迷糊
You're having a little trouble.
想停手了吗
You want to stop now?
可能还不想
Maybe not?
我没子弹了
I'm out!
快
Come on!
四人一组  搜索办公室
Teams of four, sweep the offices!
-亚伦  -瑞克
- Aaron! ?- Rick!
我们在电梯旁边
We're by the elevator!
结束了吗  摩根
Is it over, Morgan?
结束了吗
Is it?
什么
What?
我不对
I'm not right.
我知道  我不对
I know that -- I'm not right.
但那不代表我错了
But that doesn't make me wrong.
我不能参与其中
I can't be a part of this.
摩根
Morgan.
你是对的
You are right.
是他
It's him.
有人吗
Hello!
开门
Open the gates!
我需要帮助
I -- I need help!
我吃尽了苦头
I've been through hell!
我知道你在里面  我知道你能听见
I know you're in there! I know you can hear me!
怎么  门坏了吗
What, is the gate broken?
我叫他们上点油的
I-I've told them to oil that --
门没坏
The gate's not broken.
你为什么开着加百利的车
What are you doing with Gabriel's car?
他在哪
Where is he?
我不知道你说的是谁
I don't know who that is.
车停在那我就开了
The -- The car was just there.
那你来这做什么
So what are you doing here?
我住在这
I live here.
这是我家
This is my home.
我建了这个地方
I built this place.
你当时不在
Uh, you weren't here for that,
但是有人可不是现在才蹦出来的
but some of us didn't just show up.
闭上你的臭嘴
Shut your damn mouth!
你真的打算站在那
You're really gonna stand there and pretend
假装自己没出卖我们
you didn't try to sell us out,
没向救世军出卖这地方吗
sell this place out to the Saviors?
我是头脑清醒的
I was working for the side of sanity.
我努力营造和平
I was working for peace.
你威胁要把别人逐出这里
You threatened to kick people out.
我想要救人
I tried to save lives.
现在这些人都成了炮灰
Now those people are cannon fodder.
这些人想通过抗争过上更好的生活
Those people are fighting for a better life.
听着  "驱逐全家"都是尼根的点子
Look, the "Throwing out the families" Line was all Negan.
是他逼我说了那些可怕的话
He made me say those horrible things.
我去找他们  是是是
I went to them in -- in -- in --
你知道的  是为了
you know, in the interest of --
继续诚信友好的外交往来
of furthering good-faith diplomacy.
我想要救人
I tried to save lives.
有些人
Some people,
如果没有被复仇洗脑
without opinions colored by a preoccupation with vengeance,
可能会将之称为英雄行为
might call that heroic.
你只是为了你自己
You were looking out for yourself.
你是去背叛我们的
You went there to betray us.
去警告尼根我们要去攻击他们
To warn Negan that we were gonna fight.
你把凯尔拽到那里时  就是这样告诉他的
That's what you told Kal when you dragged him there.
所以凯尔才抛下你走了
It's why Kal left you there.
凯尔  凯尔有妄想症
Kal? Pfft. Kal is delusional.
你他妈说什么
What the hell?
凯尔
Kal!
得了  兄弟
Hey. C'mon, man.
你知道自己戏挺多的
Y-You -- You know you can be dramatic.
高粱煎饼那事  记得吗
That -- That thing with the sorghum, huh?
你指你吃了一个小姑娘煎饼那事吗
You mean when you ate a little girl's pancakes?
我没吃那些煎饼
I did not eat those pancakes!
听着  不管怎样
Listen, for what it's worth,
我没有对你的目标造成任何负面影响
I did exactly zero harm to your cause.
尼根早就全知道了
Negan already knew everything.
再见  格雷戈里
Goodbye, Gregory.
等等  不要  求你了
Wait! No! Please!
好吧  我去那里是因为害怕
I -- All right, I went there because I was scared,
行吗
all right?
我知道你们打算开战
I knew you were going to fight,
而我  我并不想参与
and -- and I didn't want to be complicit.
因为我觉得你们赢不了
Because I didn't think you could win.
可我现在看到了  你早就看到的东西
But I see now what -- what you saw all along.
我明白了那些救世军根本不讲道理
That -- That -- that the Saviors can't be reasoned with.
确实只能与他们开战
That fighting them is the only way.
是我错了
I was wrong.
我犯了错  我很抱歉
I-I-I made a mistake, and I'm sorry.
求你了  玛姬
Please, Maggie.
我们都是普通人
We're all just human beings
会犯错误  有缺点  也有恐惧
with faults and flaws and -- and fears!
可你真是这样的人吗
But i-is this who you are?
毫不仁慈
H-Have you no mercy?
毫无人性
Have you no humanity?
毫无善心
Have you no charity?
求你了
Please!
打开门吧
Open the gate.
打开你的心
Open your heart.
别眼睁睁看一个活生生的人死在外面
Don't leave another human being out here to die!
放他进来
Let him in.
他的那些所作所为...
?With everything he did...
为什么
Why?
不值得杀他
He's not worth killin'.
至少现在不值得
Not yet, anyway.
你不会后悔的
You won't regret this.
我已经改过了
I've changed.
我现在坚信不疑
I-I'm a believer now.
你会看到的
You'll see.
玛姬
Uhhh...Maggie?
绝对不能让他们进来
We are not letting them in!
绝对不行
No way!
他们过去做过的事
With what they did?
现在的所作所为
With what they do?
-他们就是禽兽  -格雷戈里
- They are monsters! - Gregory...
不行  这里不是杀手的庇护所
?No! This is not a sanctuary for killers.
这是拿所有人的安全在冒险
We'll be putting the safety of everyone in jeopardy!
走开
Get out of here.
我知道他们是什么人
I know what they are.
-我亲眼看过...  -格雷戈里
I have stared into the face of th-- Gregory!
走
Go.
发生了那么多  他居然回来了
He actually came back after all that.
而我居然放他进来了
And I actually let him in.
无意冒犯  耶稣
No offense, Jesus,
但我跟那个混蛋想法一样
but I kind of agree with that prick.
许多人拖家带口在这里
There are families here.
有很多孩子
Children.
后面有两部空拖车
There's two empty trailers out back.
我们可以把他们锁在里面
We could lock them up in there
派人日夜看守  直到事情过去
with 'round-the-clock guards until this whole thing is over.
到时候再说
And go from there...
你知道他们怎么对待我们
You know what they've done to us.
怎么掠夺我们
What they've taken from us.
我当然知道
Of course I do.
但他们已经投降了
But they surrendered.
耶稣
Jesus...
我们不能放他们回去
We can't let them go,
也不能杀他们
and we can't kill them.
不行
We can't.
亚伦
Aaron!
他在那
He's there.
埃里克在那
Eric's there.
我不能
I can't...
我不能就让他...
I can't just let him...
亚伦
Aaron...
那已经不是他了
that's not him.
好的
Okay.
-我们得走了  -不  不
- We gotta go. - No. No.
走吧
Come on.
枪不在这
Guns aren't here.
我们得立刻撤了  大家
We gotta go right now, people!
他们会引开尸群
They're gonna pull away the herd,
但我们也不能冒险
but we aren't taking any chances!
在里面找到的吗
She was inside?
是的
She was.
我得
I have a --
去一个地方  达里尔骑摩托
I have a stop to make, and Daryl's got his bike.
也许你或斯科特可以带她回去
Maybe she can go back with you or Scott...
我带她吧
She can go with me.
我可以送她去山顶寨
I can, uh, t-take her to the Hilltop.
她在那里比较安全
She'll be safe there.
亚伦
Aaron.
你确定吗
You sure?
埃里克和我本来
Eric and I were gonna go up...
打算完事后去那边向玛姬汇报
We were gonna go there after and update Maggie.
所以我就去吧
So...that's what I'm gonna do.
拜托了
Please.
我必须去
I have to.
好
Yeah.
她的名字叫格雷西
Her name's Gracie.
你好  格雷西
Hey, Gracie.
回家见
See you back home.
你确定你想一个人和那群混蛋交涉吗
Sure you wanna talk to them assholes alone?
确定
Yeah.
这样才能成事
That's how it gets done.
好吧  如果你太久没回来
All right. You're gone too long,
我就去找你
I'm gonna come lookin' for you.
就这么定了
That's the plan.
喂
Hey!
你是一个人
You're alone.
一定是的
You got to be.
树后面藏不下两个人
There's not enough room for two of you behind that tree.
而且尸群要来了
And there's a herd coming.
我就说说
I'm just sayin'.
要不这样吧
Hey, I tell you what...
我们谈个交易
...we'll make you a deal.
你放下枪  走出来
You drop your gun and come on out --
说出我们想知道的事
you tell us what we need to know.
只要这样做
You do that,
你就能开走一辆车
you can take a car.
你可以走  你可以活
You go. You live.
如何
How about it?
我凭什么信你
Why should I trust you?
因为我向你做出了承诺
'Cause I'm giving you my word.
如今没多少有意义的东西
There's not a lot ?that's worth much these days,
但一个男人的承诺
but a man's word...
应该是有所意义的  对吧
that's got to mean something, right?
好...好吧
O-O-Okay.
你们想知道什么
W-What do you wanna know?
你们这里有0.50勃朗宁重机枪吗
You ever have any m2 Browning .50-caliber guns here?
曾有过一段时间
We did. For a while.
枪哪去了
What happened to 'em?
昨天被调到另一个哨站了
They got sent to another outpost yesterday.
哪一个
Which one?
加文的哨站
It was Gavin's --
在这里以西
it's west of here.
我能走了吗
Can I, uh -- Can...Can I go?
哪队人去了加文的哨站
Which team's at Gavin's?
所有人都在  陛下
Everyone is accounted for, Your Majesty.
以西结
Ezekiel?
没死一个
Not one.
我们得搜一遍基地
We need to sweep the compound.
依你的建议和计划行事
Your counsel, your plan.
我去看看
Let me take a look...
既然我们要在这里待一会儿
If we're gonna be here a while,
不如顺手把它们解决了
might as well take care of them.
反正都要解决的  哥们
We should do it either way, man.
不是我们  就是他们
We or they.
你死我活
One or the other.
不可能...
It cannot be --
-快散开  -掩护国王
- Scatter, now! - Cover the King!
不
No!